A Guide to the Asia Society Exhibition files FA258
Rockefeller Archive Center
Asia Society Exhibition files
1960 January-1975 May
Rockefeller Archive Center
Asia Society
FA258
55 Cubic Feet 125 document boxes and 1 oversize box.
125 document boxes and 1 oversize box.
Arrangement
The Exhibitions are arranged chronologically. Within each Exhibition, the files are arranged alphabetically, with material in each folder arranged in reverse chronological order. Folder titles, for the most part, reflect the filing system used by the Asia House Gallery staff at the time the files were created.
Scope and Contents
In late 1959, The Asia Society moved into its new headquarters at Asia House, 112 East 64th Street, New York City. The second floor of the seven-floor building housed two galleries running the width of the house, one in front and one in back - in future, to be known as Asia House Gallery.
On January 7, 1960, the first exhibition to be held at Asia House, "Masterpieces of Asian Art in American Collections", opened to the public. In the Foreword to the catalogue for this exhibition, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, President of The Asia Society, wrote, "It is a source of great pleasure and satisfaction to all of us associated with The Asia Society to be able to present this important collection of Asian art as the first exhibition in our gallery. The assembling of this striking array of art objects, all of them from American collections, will, we hope, prove of value in further appreciation for the artistic achievements of the East."
The Asia Society Exhibition files document the exhibitions held over the next 15 years. From January 1960 through March 1975, a total of 50 exhibitions took place at Asia House. Most were chosen by guest curators who were experts in their particular field. Pieces were loaned by private collectors, by other museums, and on a few occasions, by the governments of the countries whose objects were being displayed. Many of the exhibitions were circulated to other museums throughout North America. Documents concerning lectures and private openings and events, and newspaper and magazine articles about the exhibitions shed further light on the history of Asia House Gallery during this time period.
This collection, although documenting only a small part of The Asia Society's history, provides visible and artistically beautiful examples of how the Society seeks "to further greater understanding and mutual appreciation between the United States and the peoples of Asia." [Source: Catalogue for "Mingei: Folk Arts of Old Japan, 1965]
Custodial History
The material in this collection was originally donated to the Smithsonian Institution's Archives of American Art by the Asia Society on November 12, 1976. Pursuant to the deed of gift, the Archives of American Art had the authority to transfer ownership of these records to the Rockefeller Archive Center, which it did in 2009.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was transferred and donated to the RAC by the Smithsonian Institution's Archives of American Art in 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for researchd. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
- Masterpieces of Asian Art in American Collections, Exhibited: 1960 January-February
  Biographical / Historical
  Objects in the Exhibition were chosen by a committee under the direction of Laurence Sickman, Director of the William Rockhill Nelson Gallery-Atkins Museum, Kansas City, Missouri. Other members of the committee were: Stella Kramrisch, Curator of Indian art, Philadelphia Museum of Art, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Maurice Dimand, Curator of Near Eastern art, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York City (retired); Sherman E. Lee, Director, The Cleveland Museum of Art, Cleveland, Ohio; and Harold F. Stern, Assistant in Japanese art, Freer Gallery, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.
  - Catalogue, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Costs, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Daily Reports, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gallery Publicity, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Installation Design, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Installation Photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Loan Forms, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photos, Duplicates, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photos Not in Exhibit, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Transparencies, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Work Sheets, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Haniwa, Exhibited: 1960 March-April
  The Exhibition was sent to the United States by the Government of Japan to commemmorate the centennial of United States-Japanese diplomatic relations. The Tokyo National Museum, the Society for International Cultural Relations (KBS), Tokyo, and the Japan Society, New York, were sponsors of the Exhibition. Objects in the Exhibition were selected by Mr. Seiroku Noma, Chief Curator of the Tokyo National Museum. Mr. Noma wrote the introduction to the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Japan Society, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Museum of Modern Art, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gallery Publicity, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Import/Export, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Loan Forms, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Photos, Duplicates, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Gandhara Sculpture, Exhibited: 1960 May-June
  Objects in the Exhibition were loaned by the Government of Pakistan. Guest director of the Exhibition was Benjamin Rowland, Jr., Acting Curator of Oriental Art, Fogg Museum, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Dr. Rowland prepared the scholarly text for the illustrated catalogue of the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Checklists, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Smithsonian Institution, 1958-1961, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gallery Publicity, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Loan Forms, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Loan Forms: Stucco Pieces, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Work Sheets, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Paintings by Ch'i Pai-shih, Exhibited: 1960 October-November
  All the objects in the Exhibition were from the private collection of Mr. Yakichiro Suma of Tokyo, Japan.
  - Catalogue, 1960, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Daily Reports, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Loan Forms, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Rajput Painting, Exhibited: 1960 December-1961 January
  The objects in the Exhibition were chosen from foremost American collections with additions from England. Guest Director of the Exhibition was Dr. Sherman E. Lee, Director of the Cleveland Museum of Art, Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Catalogue, 1960-1961, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961, 1963-1964, 1967, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Costs, Exhibitions, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Daily Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition List, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Installation Photos, Duplicates, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Loan Forms, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Opening, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Photos Not in Exhibit, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Arts of the Han Dynasty, Exhibited: 1961 February-March
  The Exhibition, which was organized, arranged and catalogued by Mr. Henry Trubner, Curator of the Far Eastern Department of the Royal Ontario Museum, Toronto, Canada, was presented by the Chinese Art Society of America. The Asia Society made their gallery available and contributed to the financing of the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Daily Reports, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Gallery File, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Loan Forms, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Loan Receipts and Receipts of Delivery, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Peasant and Nomad Rugs of Asia, Exhibited: 1961 September-November
  Guest Director for the Exhibition was Maurice S. Dimand, Curator Emeritus of Near Eastern Art at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, New York. Dr. Dimand wrote the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Daily Reports, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Exhibition List, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Loan Agreement Forms, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Khmer Sculpture, Exhibited: 1961 November-1962 January
  The Exhibition was assembled by George Montgomery, Director of the Asia House Gallery. The catalogue for the Exhibition contains a critical essay by Ad Reinhardt entitled "Angkor and Art", and a partial account by Chou Ta-kuan of his travels to the city of Angkor in 1296 A.D.
  - Catalogue, 1959, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Costs, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Daily Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Griswold Collection-Breezewood, Maryland, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Loan Agreement Forms, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Loans Completed, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Costs-Exhibitions
  - Costs-Exhibitions, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Costs-Exhibitions, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Costs-Exhibitions, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Costs-Exhibitions, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 64)
- The Art of Southern Sung China, Exhibited: 1962 February-April
  The Exhibition of sculpture, painting and ceramics from the period of Southern Sung China (1127-1279 A.D.) was chosen by James Cahill, Associate Curator of Chinese Art, Freer Gallery of Art, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., from major American collections.
  - Catalogue, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence: James Cahill, 1961-1962, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Daily Reports, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Installation, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Loan Agreement Forms, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Publicity Photos, undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Gods of Asia, Exhibited: 1962 May-July
  The Exhibition of sculpture and painting was assembled by George Montgomery, Director of the Asia House Gallery.
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Daily Reports, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Labels, undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Loan Agreement Forms, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 75)
- The Art of India/Stone Sculpture, Exhibited: 1962 September-November
  The selection of sculpture in the Exhibition was made by George Montgomery, former Director of the Asia House Gallery, with the assistance of Aschwin Lippe, Associate Curator of Far Eastern Art of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, New York. Mr. Lippe wrote the introductory essay for the catalogue of the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Daily Reports, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Loan Agreement Forms, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Publicity, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 81)
- Muslim Miniature Painting, Exhibited: 1962 December-1963 February
  The Exhibition came to Asia House following its showing earlier in the year at the Fondazione Giorgio Cini of Venice, Italy. The 125 miniatures and manuscripts were all from major American collections. Dr. Ernst J. Grube, Assistant Curator of Near Eastern Art at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, New York, selected the material for the Exhibition and composed the scholarly catalogue that accompanied it.
  - Catalogue, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence: Ernst J. Grube, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Daily Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Guest Pages, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Loan Agreements, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 88)
- Tea Taste in Japanese Art, Exhibited: 1963 February-April
  The Exhibition, containing ceramics, paintings, lacquers and the utensils of the Japanese tea ceremony, was organized for Asia House by Sherman E. Lee, Director of the Cleveland Museum of Art, Cleveland, Ohio. Dr. Lee wrote the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue, 1962-1963, 1967, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence: Sherman E. Lee, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Daily Reports, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Guest Pages, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Installation Photos, undated (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Loan Agreements, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Press, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Soko Sen Performing Tea Ceremony, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 97)
- The Evolution of the Buddha Image, Exhibited: 1963 May-June
  The selection of material for the Exhibition was made by Benjamin Rowland, Jr., of Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Dr. Rowland also wrote the text of the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1963, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Correspondence: Jiro Enjoji and John Rosenfield, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Correspondence: Benjamin Rowland, Jr., 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Daily Reports, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Guest Pages, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Loan Agreements, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Packing and Shipping, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Publicity, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 107)
- Contemporary Japanese Calligraphy, Exhibited: 1963 July-August
  The Exhibition of modern Japanese calligraphy was loaned to the Asia Society by the Japan Society. The material exhibited was brought to the United States for circulation throughout the country by the American Federation of Arts.
  - Publicity, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 108)
- Iranian Ceramics, Exhibited: 1963 October-December
  The items in the Exhibition were selected by Charles K. Wilkinson, Curator Emeritus of Near Eastern Art at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, New York. Mr. Wilkinson also wrote the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Correspondence A-M, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Correspondence N-Z, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence: Charles K. Wilkinson, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Daily Reports, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Dinner Party, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Guest Book, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Loan Agreements, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Publicity, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Slide Permission Letters, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Thank You Letters, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 120)
- The Art of Mughal India, Exhibited: 1964 January-March
  The material in the Exhibition was selected by Stuart Cary Welch, Lecturer in Fine Arts, the William Hayes Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Mr. Welch also wrote the catalogue of the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, undated (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Correspondence A-M: Domestic, 1962-1965 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Correspondence N-Z: Domestic, 1962-1964, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Correspondence A-M: Foreign, 1961-1964 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - Correspondence N-Z: Foreign, 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - Correspondence: Stuart Cary Welch, 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 127)
  - Daily Reports, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 128)
  - Guest Book, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 129)
  - Loan Agreements, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  - Photo Permissions: "Handicraft in Pakistan", 1964 (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - Publicity, 1963-1968 (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - Slide Permission Letters, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 133)
- The Art of Nepal, Exhibited: 1964 May-August
  The Exhibition of Nepali sculpture, paintings, and manuscripts was selected by Stella Kramrisch, Curator of Indian Art, the Philadelphia Museum of Art, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and was presented under the patronage of His Majesty, Mahendra Bir Bikram Shah Deva, King of Nepal. Dr. Kramrisch wrote the text for catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Catalogue: Corrections and Suggestions, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - Catalogue: Corrections and Suggestions, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 135)
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1963-1965, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 136)
  - Catalogue: Final Proof with Corrections, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 137)
  - Catalogue: Final Proof with Corrections, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 138)
  - Catalogue: Illustrations for Introduction - Copy Negatives and Prints, undated (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - Catalogue: Introduction and Glossary, undated (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - Catalogue: Revised Edition, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 141)
  - Correspondence A-E: Domestic, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 142)
  - Correspondence F-N: Domestic, 1961, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 143)
  - Correspondence O-Z: Domestic, 1961-1964 (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Correspondence A-K: Foreign, 1962-1965 (Box 14, Folder 145)
  - Correspondence L-N: Foreign, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 146)
  - Correspondence O-Z: Foreign, 1962-1965 (Box 15, Folder 147)
  - Correspondence: General, 1961, 1963-1967, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 148)
  - Correspondence: Stella Kramrisch, 1962-1964, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 149)
  - Correspondence: Request for Contributions to Exhibit: Negative Responses, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Daily Reports, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 151)
  - Guest Book, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - Installation Information, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - Installation Photos and Negatives, undated (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - Loan Agreements, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - Loan Agreements, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 156)
  - Loans Removed from Show, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 157)
  - Opening: Invitations, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 158)
  - Photos: Paintings and Manuscripts Not in Exhibition, undated (Box 16, Folder 159)
  - Photos: Sculpture Not in Exhibition, undated (Box 17, Folder 160)
  - Publicity, 1963-1964, 1966, 1968, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 161)
  - Slide Permission Letters, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 162)
- Masters of the Japanese Print, Exhibited: 1964 October-December
  The Exhibition of 100 Japanese woodcuts was selected by Margaret Gentles, Associate Curator of Oriental Art, The Art Institute of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois. Miss Gentles also wrote the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Acoustiguide Script, undated (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1964-19965, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, Author's Corrections, undated (Box 17, Folder 165)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, Final, undated (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, Original, undated (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1963-1965 (Box 18, Folder 168)
  - Correspondence: Margaret Gentles, 1963-1965 (Box 18, Folder 169)
  - Daily Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 170)
  - Guest Book, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 171)
  - Installation, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - Loan Agreements, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - Opening, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 174)
  - Photos: Not in Exhibit, undated (Box 19, Folder 175)
  - Publicity, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 176)
  - Slide Permission Letters, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 177)
- Relics of Ancient China from the Collection of Dr. Paul Singer, Exhibited: 1965 January-March
  Pieces for the Exhibition were selected by Max Loehr, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Professor of Oriental Art, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts, from the extensive private collection of Dr. Paul Singer. Dr. Loehr also wrote the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Acoustiguide Script, undated (Box 19, Folder 178)
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 179)
  - Catalogue: Dr. Singer's Original Cards, undated (Box 19, Folder 180)
  - Catalogue: Galleys, Master Set, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 181)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, undated (Box 19, Folder 182)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, Original, undated (Box 20, Folder 183)
  - Catalogue: Notes, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 184)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1965, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 185)
  - Daily Reports-January, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 186)
  - Daily Reports-February, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 187)
  - Daily Reports-March-April, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 188)
  - Guest Book, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 189)
  - Installation, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 190)
  - Installation: Photos, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 191)
  - Loan Agreement and Insurance Claim, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 192)
  - Opening, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 193)
  - Photos: Inferior, undated (Box 21, Folder 194)
    General
    Folder 1 of 3
  - Photos: Inferior, undated (Box 21, Folder 195)
    Folder 2 of 3
  - Photos: Inferior, undated (Box 21, Folder 196)
    Folder 3 of 3
  - Photos: Not Illustrated, undated (Box 21, Folder 197)
  - Photos: Not in Exhibit, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 198)
    Folder 1 of 2
  - Photos: Not in Exhibit, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 199)
    Folder 2 of 2
  - Publicity, 1964-1966, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 200)
  - Slide Information Sheet, undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
- Mingei: Folk Arts of Old Japan, Exhibited: 1965 May-July
  Material for the Exhibition was chosen by Hugo Munsterberg, Professor of Art History, New York State University College at New Paltz, New York. Dr. Munsterberg also wrote the catalogue for the Exhibition.
  - Acoustiguide Script, undated (Box 22, Folder 202)
  - Arts of Japan from the Munsterberg Collection: Annotated Catalogue, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 203)
  - Catalogue, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 204)
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 205)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, Copy, undated (Box 23, Folder 206)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, Original, undated (Box 23, Folder 207)
  - Correspondence A-L, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 208)
  - Correspondence M-Z, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 209)
  - Correspondence: Hugo Munsterberg, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 210)
  - Daily Reports, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  - Exhibition Lists, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - Guest Pages, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 213)
  - Installation, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 214)
  - Installation: Photos and Negatives, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 215)
  - Loan Agreements; Receipts of Delivery, 1964-1967 (Box 24, Folder 216)
  - Opening, 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 217)
  - Photos: Inferior, undated (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Photos: Not in Exhibit, undated (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Publicity, 1965, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 220)
- Gods, Thrones, and Peacocks, Exhibited: 1965 September-December
  The paintings in the Exhibition were chosen and catalogued by Stuart Cary Welch, Assistant in Islamic Art at the Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts, while the catalogue was jointly prepared by Mr. Welch and his colleague, Milo Cleveland Beach, Acting-Curator for the Department of Asiatic Art, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Massachusetts. After its showing at Asia House, the Exhibition subsequently was displayed at The Baltimore Museum of Art, Baltimore, Maryland, and the Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, Utica, New York.
  - Acoustiguide Script, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 221)
  - Catalogue: Annotated, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - Catalogue: Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 25, Folder 223)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript, Original, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 224)
  - Catalogue: Manuscript and Proofs, undated (Box 25, Folder 225)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1966, 1969-1971 (Box 25, Folder 226)
  - Daily Reports, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 227)
  - Guest Book, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 228)
  - Installation, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 229)
  - Loan Agreements, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 230)
  - Opening, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 231)
  - Publicity, 1965-1968 (Box 26, Folder 232)
  - Slide Permission Letters, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 233)
  - Travel of Exhibition, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 234)
- Ancient Art from Afghanistan, Exhibited: 1966 January-March